ILGWU New York Cloak Joint Board's Advisory Commission on the Cloak, Suit, and Skirt Industry in New York Records 5780/161
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU New York Cloak Joint Board's Advisory Commission on the Cloak, Suit, and Skirt Industry in New York Records
1924-1959
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
New York Cloak Joint Board
Advisory Commission on the Cloak, Suit, and Skirt Industry in New York
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/161
2.17 cubic feet
2.2 linear ft.
Records (documents).
The collection contains records relating to New York Governor Smith's Advisory Commission on the Cloak, Suit, and Skirt Industry in New York, including volumes on the hearings before the commission in 1924 and 1925, reports, and recommendations. Also included is the report of the New York Cloak Joint Board for the years 1956 to 1959.
5521554
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, June 10, 2009
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 15, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Beginning in March 1924, the ILGWU and the Joint Board of Cloak and Dressmakers' Union began negotiations with the Merchants' Ladies' Garment Association (jobbers), the Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers' Protective Association (manufacturers), and the American Cloak and Suit Manufacturers' Association (sub-manufacturers). When no agreement could be reached by June 1924, New York Governor Alfred E. Smith appointed a Special Advisory Commission consisting of George Gordon Battle (Chairman), Herbert Lehman, Arthur Wolf, Lindsay Rogers, and Bernard Schientag (State Industrial Commissioner). Representing the union and associations were Morris Hillquit (ILGWU), Samuel Blumberg (Merchants' Ladies' Garment Association) and William Klein (Cloak and Suit Manufacturers' Protective Association). Public hearings took place between June 17 and June 25, and on June 27, recommendations were submitted. Accepted by the union, sub-manufacturers, and manufacturers, the jobbers refused until July 7, 1924 when the Merchants' Association agreed to the terms of the Governors' Commission.
Scope and Contents
June 17, 1924 began the first hearing of the Special Commission to study the situation in the Cloak and Suit Industry and be able to offer recommendations to avert any impending strike. The hearings are in bound volumes and include June 17-19, 1924; June 20-23, 1924; June 24-July 11, 1924; July 15-August 1, 1924; August 12-October 2, 1924; and January 2-April 15, 1925.
The Hearings continue into 1925, and additionally, there is the final Report of the Investigation from March 10, 1925. There are also additional reports that were created as the result of the investigation including "Wages and Wage Scales, 1925," Final Recommendations from May 1926, the Meeting of the Special Mediation Commission in the New York Cloak and Suit Industry from March 6, 1926 (same individuals involved). Also included in the collection is the
New York Cloak Joint Board Report from 1956-1959.
Supplemental material can be found in collection 5780/165 Governor Smith's Hearing and Arbitration Files which includes the typed transcripts from the hearings of the Special Commission appointed by Governor Smith to investigate and arbitrate the existing differences between the ILGWU and the associations of manufacturers and jobbers. Taking place at the office of the State Labor Department in New York City, the records contain hearings that date between July 15, 1924 and October 27, 1924. In the form of questions and answers between the Special Commission and the representatives of the ILGWU and manufacturers' associations, discussion focuses on the role of designers within manufacturing, conditions in the industry, the responsibility of jobbers and sub-manufacturers, and salary and wages.
Much of the same information can also be found in collection 6036/009 Governor's Advisory Commission. Cloak, Suit & Skirt Industry.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/165: ILGWU Governor Smith's Hearings and Arbitration with Various Associations Records 6036/009: Governor's Advisory Commission on the Cloak, Suit and Skirt Industry
Women's clothing industry -- United States.; Women's clothing industry -- New York (State); Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States.; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State); Clothing workers -- United States.; Clothing workers -- New York (State); Industrial relations -- United States.; Industrial relations -- New York (State); Smith, Alfred Emanuel, -- 1873-1944.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. -- New York Cloak Joint Board.; Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers' Protective Association (New York, N.Y.). Governor's Advisory Commission
5521554
- Governor's Advisory Commission. Vol.1, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  June, 1924. Pgs.1-277
- Governor's Advisory Commission. Vol.2, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  June, 1924. Pgs.278-567
- Governor's Advisory Commission. Vol.3, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  June 1924 - July 1924. Pgs.568-799
- Governor's Advisory Commission. Vol.4, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  July 1924 - August 1924. Pgs.800-1100
- Governor's Advisory Commission. Vol.5, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  August 1924 - October 1924. Pgs.1101-1392
- Governor's Advisory Commission. Vol.6, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  January 1925 - April 1925. Pgs.1393-1813
- Governor's Advisory Commission. Wages and Wage Scales, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  3 copies.
- Governor's Advisory Commission. Report of an Investigation, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Governor's Advisory Commission. Final Recommendations, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- New York Cloak Joint Board Report 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  2 copies.
- Meeting of the Special Mediation Commission, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  6 March, 1926
- Governor's Advisory Commission. Hearing., 1925 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  14 April, 1925. Loose with other pages.
- Governor's Advisory Commission. Hearing., 1925 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  20 April, 1925. Loose with other pages.
- ILGWU Archives - Hearings held by Special Committee of Arbitration Appointed by Governor to Arbitrate Differences (Box 3)
  - Hearings held by Special Committee of Arbitration appointed by Governor to arbitrate differences between ILGWU and various manufacturers associations, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 1)